gfusa.org 2015-06-17

# Privacy Policy | Grameen Foundation | Connecting the World's Poor to Their Potential

Grameen Foundation (“GF” or “we”) respects the right to privacy of our clients (“you”) and is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust. This Privacy Policy explains what kind of private data we collect from our clients; why we collect such information; how we share, transfer and secure private data; and your privacy rights.

## **What Private Data Do We Collect?**

Grameen Foundation is a non-governmental organization whose charitable mission is to help the world's poorest – especially women – improve their lives and escape poverty by providing them with access to appropriate financial services, life-changing information and unique income-generating opportunities.  In order to carry out our mission and with your express consent, we collect the following data from individuals and organizations:

  * Personal information about clients benefiting from Grameen Foundation’s programs
  * Organizational data from institutions that Grameen Foundation works with
  * Information to track our loans and investments, such as financial reporting and annual financial statements
  * Information from individuals interested in entering our Bankers without Borders® database of potential volunteers
  * Personal data from our donors
  * Personal information to access certain features on our website that allow you to send and receive information to and from us and to donate to us (we collect credit card information only for the purpose of processing your donation)
  * Information for internal tracking of personnel and financial operations

## **Why Do We Collect Private Data?**

We collect and otherwise use private data from our clients for specific purposes that are limited to furthering our charitable mission.  Grameen Foundation does not collect or otherwise use private data without legal authorization, contractual obligation and/or our clients’ express written consent. 

The information we collect helps us to: (1) design and improve products and services that meet our clients’ needs; (2) monitor the effectiveness of our programs so that we, our investors, local governments and our other third-party partners know who we are reaching with our products and services and where we need to improve our outreach; (3) evaluate individual skill sets and match them to corresponding needs in the field; (4) track health or agricultural information of our clients so we can give them (or their health care providers) relevant and useful information; (5) monitor our investments; (6) conduct research in the aggregate in order to understand our global and regional poverty outreach; and (7) track personnel and financial operations for internal purposes.

## **With Whom Do We Share Private Data?**

With your express written consent, we may share your private data with organizations that are related to us, with our service providers, and with our third-party partners.  We may also share aggregated and anonymous data with our third-party partners and with the general public on a publicly-accessible website.  Occasionally, we may be required by legal request, subpoena, government reporting obligation or other legal process or obligation to disclose our clients’ private data.  Similarly, as permitted by law, we may disclose the information we collect to fight fraud or to protect the rights or property of Grameen Foundation, our clients, our donors or others, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it.

## **Transfer of Private Data**

In connection with any of the uses or sharing of private data described in this Privacy Policy, we may transfer our clients’ private data internationally, to an organization outside the country in which the information is collected.  Grameen Foundation will follow all data protection protocols required by applicable local laws.

### **Security**

Grameen Foundation is committed to protecting your private data against unlawful destruction, accidental loss or alteration, or unauthorized disclosure or access.  First, we only collect and otherwise use private data that is relevant to, proportional to and in furtherance of the charitable purposes for which it is obtained.  Second, we do not store your personal or sensitive information any longer than is necessary to satisfy those purposes.  Third, when we store or otherwise use your personal or sensitive information, we use reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards that are designed to protect and secure private data adequately.  For example:

  * When you donate to Grameen Foundation via our website, your donation information is encrypted and transmitted by way of a secure connection  (Note: No security systems are perfect, and we cannot guarantee the security of our clients’ information)
  * All sensitive information is stored anonymously
  * We ensure that the entities with whom we share our clients’ private data have agreed to provide sufficient guarantees, in compliance with local law, to secure and protect that data
  * We annually audit our Privacy Policy in order to ensure internal compliance, to ensure compliance with local law, and to make any modifications to the Policy that may be necessary

### **Your Privacy Rights**

You have a right to access and control your private data that we have collected and stored.  Accordingly, you may ask at reasonable intervals for a copy of any personal or sensitive information about you that we have collected and stored.  We will provide you with a copy with reasonable promptness and at no expense.  You may also ask that we correct, update or delete any of your private data.

## **Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information**

We also collect non-personal information – data in a form that does not provide direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

### **Normal Web Browsing**

The information we gather during normal browsing comes from two sources: standard server logs collect information such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address, domain name, browser type, operating system; and information such as the site that referred you to us, the files you downloaded, the pages you visited, and the dates/times of those visits. We may use this information to improve our outreach and communications about our work.

Additionally, if you have come into the site from one of our newsletters or from a site that has requested a link to us, we will ask your browser to accept a cookie that carries a general marketing source code with you as you browse through the site, in order to help us match referring site to donations made. This cookie does not capture or hold any personally identifying information about you, and is deleted when you end your session by leaving our site or closing your browser.

### **Cookies and Other Technologies**

When you visit our website, we might store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” (i.e. a small piece of text that stores information on your browser in your computer’s hard drive) or similar file. We use conversion tracking cookies as part of campaigns in order to analyze trends, gather broad demographic information, and monitor site traffic patterns that can help us further develop and improve the design and functionality of our site. Similarly, we also use cookies for ”retargeting” in our internet advertising campaigns so that third party vendors, including Google, can show you advertising about Grameen Foundation as you browse the internet. Retargeting is a marketing tool that identifies you as a previous visitor to the Grameen Foundation website and targets you for specific outreach messages, encouraging you to revisit our website or consider donating. The cookies will only be used to obtain non-personal information (you will be anonymous). If you prefer, you can usually set your browser to refuse cookies, or to notify you when you receive a new cookie. You can also opt out of receiving cookies on the Grameen Foundation website for Google advertising by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page (<http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/#toc-edit>).

## **Contacting Us**

If you have any other questions, requests, comments or concerns related to this Privacy Policy, please contact us in writing at the following address:  
Grameen Foundation  
Steve Andersen , Chief Technology Officer  
2101 4th Avenue, Suite 1550   
Seattle, WA 98121

### **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time.  However, we will communicate any significant modifications of this Privacy Policy to our clients. 

**Effective Date:** This Privacy Policy is Effective as of December 9 2013

### Updating your personal information

You may contact us any time to review the personal information we have on file and or to request corrections at:

Development Department  
Grameen Foundation  
1101 15th Street NW, 3rd floor  
Washington, DC 20005  
(toll free) 1-888-764-3872 x125 or outside the U.S. (202) 628-3560 x125  
development [at] grameenfoundation.org (Contact us by email)

In addition, if you signed up to receive any of our online newsletters or communications, you received a welcome message immediately after you signed up. It contains a web address where you can access and update your online account information. If you do allow others, including family or household members, to access Grameen Foundation members-only services, please understand that you are responsible for the actions of those individuals.

### Notice to contributors:

FLORIDA: A copy of the official registration and financial information may be obtained from the Division of Consumer Services by calling toll-free, within the state, 1-800-HELP-FLA. Registration does not imply endorsement, approval or recommendation by the state. MARYLAND: For the cost of postage and copying, documents and information filed under the Maryland charitable organizations laws can be obtained from the Secretary of State, Charitable Division, State House, Annapolis, MD 21401. MICHIGAN: Grameen Foundation USA’s Michigan registration number is: MICS 24720. NEW JERSEY: Information filed with the Attorney General concerning this charitable solicitation may be obtained from the Attorney General of the State of New Jersey by calling 973-504-6215. Registration with the Attorney General does not imply endorsement. NEW YORK: A copy of the latest annual report can be obtained by writing to Grameen Foundation USA, 1101 15th St., NW, 3rd Floor, Washington, DC 20005 or from the Office of the Attorney General by writing the Charities Bureau, 120 Broadway, New York, NY 10271. North Carolina: Financial information about Grameen Foundation USA and a copy of its license are available from the State Solicitation Licensing Branch at 1-919- 807-2214. The license is not an endorsement by the state. PENNSYLVANIA: The official registration and financial information of Grameen Foundation USA may be obtained from the Pennsylvania Department of state by calling toll free, within Pennsylvania, 1 (800) 732-0999. Registration does not imply endorsement. VIRGINIA: Financial statements are available from the State Division of Consumer Affairs, P.O. Box 1163, Richmond, VA 23218. WASHINGTON: Grameen Foundation USA is registered with the Secretary of State, information relating to our financial affairs is available from the Secretary of State, and the toll-free number for Washington residents is: 1-800-332-4483. WEST VIRGINIA: West Virginia residents may obtain a summary of the registration and financial documents from the Secretary of State, State Capitol, Charleston, WV 25305. Registration does not imply endorsement.
